DENYS NAZARENKO

FRONT END DEVELOPER

🗣 Richmond Hill, ON 📞 (647) 988-8103 🖂 denysnazarenko23@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Front End Developer with 3+ years of experience in development of complex web services. Successfully applied solid knowledge of programming fundamentals and data structures to real-world projects on daily basis to achieve the highest quality of delivered product. Driven to improve problem-solving methods and expand my technical knowledge.

Eligible to work for any employer in Canada.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Benchmark Automotive Group Inc.

Concord, ON

Front-End Developer

Nov 2022 - Present

- Optimized a website for search engines, resulting in a 5% increase in leads.
- Resolved a critical bug in a website's online financing application, preventing lost sales.
- Customized website with custom theme to improve UX, resulting in a 10% increase in website traffic.

Freelance

Front-End React Developer

Sep 2022 - Nov 2022

- Rewrote a complex web application from Vue.js to React, resulting in a 30% improvement in page load speed and a 10% increase in user engagement.
- Accomplished a 20% improvement in cross-browser compatibility, measured by reduced bug reports related to browser-specific issues, by utilizing polyfills and CSS best practices.
- Integrated Firebase as a backend solution, leading to a 50% reduction in database query response times, as measured by database performance metrics, by optimizing data retrieval and storage operations.

SE "Ukrmetrteststandart" (Ukrainian State Meteorological Enterprise)

Software Developer

Nov 2020 - Sep 2022

- Independently developed a WordPress-based website from scratch and resolved front-end bugs across the company's websites, leading to a 10% increase in user engagement and a 15% boost in site traffic.
- Created scripts to automate data backup for company servers and Windows-based computers, achieving an 80% automation rate, and effectively mitigating the risk of data loss.
- Fixed critical bugs in a production system, resulting in a 99% uptime for the system.

Luxoft

Software Developer Intern

Apr 2020 - Oct 2020

- Optimized existing Angular code to improve performance, resulting in a 10% increase in page load times.
- Met 100% of project milestones on time, as measured by Jira project schedules, by actively tracking progress, anticipating issues, and adjusting development strategies when necessary.
- Presented weekly updates on progress towards goals, resulting in better collaboration with a team.

EDUCATION

National Technical University of Ukraine – Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute, Ukraine Master's Degree – Automation and Computer-Integrated Technologies

SKILLS

Programming: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, PHP, SQL, UML.

Frameworks: React, Redux, Next.js, Node.js, Express, Jest, REST API, SPA.

Databases: MongoDB, Firebase, GraphQL, MySQL, phpMyAdmin.

Technical: HTML, CSS, SASS/SCSS, Handlebars, JSON, OOP, Git, Figma, Prettier, Webpack, Docker.